# Callum Gill

callumgill99@outlook.com | Mobile: 07729387663 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/callum-gill-6a3b17179/

Portfolio website: <a href="https://musing-poincare-55331e.netlify.app">https://musing-poincare-55331e.netlify.app</a>

#### **User Profile**

I have just completed a three-year full-time course at Edge Hill university studying web design and development. I have graduated from studies in July 2021 achieving a 2:1 in this degree. During my time on this course, I have been exposed to a range of skills from lots of fields in the web industry. Front end development (HTML, CSS, JS). Backend development (Laravel,MySQL,Firebase). Also testing/UX design/Github/Linux were covered in different modules/projects. From work experience I have developed many life skills this being teamwork, communication and being able to work under stressful conditions.

#### Education

# 2018 - 2021 Edge Hill University

BSc (Hons) Web Design and Development-2:1

- User Design Experience This module was based around UX which helped me grasp the idea of user interaction during the product creation this ultimately gaining better customer satisfaction.
- Server & Client-Side Scripting This module introduced me to the concept of full stack using larval and MySQL, this helped me understand the process of how front and back end works together to create a web application or website.
- Web Application Development This module gave knowledge of non-user testing some techniques learnt cognitive walkthrough and heuristic testing this helped me understand that some usability issues can be pre-ironed out before user testing starts
- Fundamentals of Web Coding This module gave me fundamentals of coding for the web, the core algorithms, and data structures. This was achieved by creating a command line vending machine using javascript.
- The final project was a creation of a web app which will need HTML, CSS and JS and UX/Design which encompasses some skills needed for web development and help gain valuable skills. This will also be the same for my portfolio modules without the UX elements.

### 2015 - 2017 Burnley College, Burnley

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma in Software Development

D\*D\*D

#### 2010-2015 Shuttleworth College

### GCSE 9 (4B,5C) including English and Maths

## **Work Experience**

# May 2016 - September 2017 McDonalds Burnham Gate, Burnley

## Responsibility's

- Being able to work in a busy environment
- Being able to work as part as team to make sure everything runs smoothly
- Checking food stock and then refilling stations so people don't run out of stock which would slow down the whole operation
- Cleaning the work stations throughout the day

## September 2015 - April 2016 Fat giraffe, Padiham

Pot wash/Waiter

#### **Interests and Activities**

Enjoy creating websites and sharing content for others to see. I also enjoy all kinds of sports I have played for a football team for 6 years while at university highly attending sports events for football and cricket this was not competitive and more aimed for fun but again have to be used to new people and best devise how to use certain people at their strengths.